Guide to the Alpha Kappa Psi, Beta Eta Chapter Records, 1929 - 1963
University Archives Duke University
Alpha Kappa Psi, Beta Eta Chapter records 1929 - 1963
Alpha Kappa Psi. Beta Eta Chapter (Duke University)
0.25 Linear Feet 300 Items
University Archives, Duke University
The Beta Eta chapter of the Alpha Kappa Psi business fraternity was established at Duke University in 1929; the chapter dissolved sometime after 1963. Records contain correspondence, bylaws, membership records, constitution, handbook, reports, certificates, and a brief history of the Beta Eta chapter of Alpha Kappa Psi.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
In accordance with the Family Education Rights and Privacy Act of 1974 as amended, Duke University permits students to inspect their education records and limits the disclosure of personally identifiable information from education records.
In off-site storage; 48 hours advance notice is required for use.
Provenance
The Alpha Kappa Psi, Beta Eta Chapter Records was received by the University Archives as a transfer in 1966 and 1981.
Historical Note
Alpha Kappa Psi was the first professional business fraternity in the United States. The fraternity was founded October 5, 1904 at New York University and is headquartered in Indianapolis, Indiana. Alpha Kappa Psi's objectives are to further the individual welfare of its members, foster scientific research in the fields of commerce, accounts, and finance, to educate the public, and to promote courses leading to degrees in business administration.
The Beta Eta chapter at Duke University was chartered on December 7, 1929 in the School of Business Administration. There were 20 original members. Carroll Cunnin was the first president. Semi-monthly meetings were held on campus in the Union Ballroom. They included discussions of current topics in business and featured local businesspeople as speakers. Members of the fraternity also visited industrial organizations, assisted professors with business-related presentations, and corresponded with large organizations on business questions. The fraternity dissolved sometime after 1963.
Collection Overview
Contains correspondence, bylaws, membership records, a constitution, a handbook, reports, certificates, and a brief historic profile pertaining to the Beta Eta chapter of the Alpha Kappa Psi business fraternity at Duke University. Materials range in date from 1929 to 1963.
Subject Headings
These and related materials may be accessed under the following subject headings in the Duke University Libraries online catalog.
Alpha Kappa Psi
Alpha Kappa Psi. Beta Eta Chapter (Duke University)
Business students -- North Carolina
Duke University -- History
Duke University -- Societies, etc
Duke University -- Students
Greek letter societies
Contents of Collection
- Container List
  - Annual report, 1961
  - Bylaws, 1955
  - Certificates, 1937-1938
  - Constitution and statutory code, 1959
  - Convention reports, 1962
  - Correspondence, ca. 1959-1963
  - Handbook of Alpha Kappa Psi, 1956, 1959
  - Membership books, 1959-1962
  - Membership book, 1960-1962
  - Minutes, 1929-1936
  - Profile, 1937
  - Charter, 1929 (Opaperfolder 1)